hey everyone welcome back to this Tosca
automation playlist and we'll talk about
another interesting feature today
so today we are going to discuss about
one of the features which is available
uh on the web tables so if you want to
verify the row and column count of a
particular web table then there is a
method which you can use to get the
total row count and the total column
count very easily from any particular
web table
so let's look at an example
now we have used this many times we have
seen how we can steer this table uh
using the constraints action mode on
different columns right but see for
example you have got a web table and you
have to verify how many rows are there
and how many columns are there okay for
verification purpose so how are you
going to do that
so for that uh there is a property
called row count and column count okay
and we'll see how we can get this and
also verify it
so for this uh I have already scanned
this module so I'm going to create a
couple of test cases here okay
so coming here I want to verify row
count
okay and uh the second test case is to
verify the column count
now I'm going to drag this module here
in verify row count and what we need to
do is we need to go to the table object
okay so this is our table object
and here we need to as I said specify a
property called row count
okay
and then we are going to assign this row
count uh into a buffer variable okay so
we are going to call it row count
and in the action mode we are going to
select buffer okay so what's going to do
it's going to get the row count using
this particular property and then it is
going to assign the value to the rocon
buffer okay
so uh that's done and then what we are
going to do is we want to verify that
this particular table has got the
specific row count right
so for that uh let's do a verification
then and for that we are going to use
the t-box evaluation tool
okay and then I just need to do a
verification here so I will be verifying
uh buffer of row count
okay
equals equals uh five
so I need to close this and then equals
equals five right
so this is a verification I want to do
and then let's move on to our next test
case which is the column count okay
so let me drag this module again here
and this time around the method is same
but the name is different
so we need to get the column count okay
and then I'm going to also create a
particular buffer called column count
and then change the action mode to
buffer here okay
um also
after this uh what we can do we can add
another test step here
again t-box evaluation tool
and here we are going to verify so we
are going to verify the column count
okay and equals equals four right
so we have got four columns and we have
got four rows okay
or actually the five rows because the
first row is the header so it should uh
actually verify correctly okay so if our
methods are correct
so let's quickly go ahead and execute
this and check if this test case passes
or it fails
okay so the test case has passed
and let's see what are the values which
has been captured here okay
so here uh the buffer with name row
count is set to 5 and then in the
evaluation
um the expected was equal to
actual so it evaluated to true and then
here column count was four and the
actual versus expected was also true so
the verification has passed right
as a best practice don't forget to
rename all your test steps and also the
test case names which I have already
done and then you should also ask that
the work state to complete it right
so as you can see it's very easy to
verify the row count and column count
this might be useful in some scenarios
where you have to put a verification on
these particular values
so that's all for this particular video
I hope you enjoyed it and you learned
something new today if you want to watch
more videos please subscribe to our
Channel and we'll come up with lots more
videos
so keep watching and keep learning Tosca